A Guide to the James Branch Cabell Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #5298-a
James Branch Cabell Collection 1936-1940
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
5298-a
ca. 30 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Gift, 1959 Dec 10
Item Listing
- Manuscripts
  - Page proof, "Of Ellen Glasgow. An Inscribed Portrait" by James Branch Cabell, 1938; Page proof, 10 p.
  - Page proof, "The Portrait" by James Branch Cabell, [ca. 1938]; Page proof, 4 p.
  - Page proof, "The Portrait" by James Branch Cabell, with autograph corrections, [ca. 1938]; Page proof, 3 p.
  - 5 line acrostic on Goudy. First & second marked proofs. Written especially for "Pilgrimage to Deepdene", 1938; TMs
  - "Of Ellen Glasgow. An Inscribed Portrait" by Ellen Glasgow and James Branch Cabell, TMs, 7 p.
  - Bibliography of works by James Branch Cabell by I. R. Brussel, n.d.; TMs, ca. 150 p.
- Letters
  - James Branch Cabell to [Earl H.] Emmons, 1936 Feb 20; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Earl H.] Emmons, 1936 Mar 3; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Earl H.] Emmons, 1936 May 9; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Earl H.] Emmons, 1936 Jun 17; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Earl H.] Emmons, 1937 May 21; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Earl H.] Emmons, 1938 Jan 9; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Earl H.] Emmons, 1938 Jan 20; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Earl H.] Emmons, 1938 Feb 5; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Earl H.] Emmons, 1938 Feb 13; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Earl H.] Emmons, 1938 Feb 28; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Earl H.] Emmons, 1938 Mar 9; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Earl H.] Emmons, 1938 Mar 11; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Earl H.] Emmons, 1938 Mar 22; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Earl H.] Emmons, 1938 Mar 23; TLS, 1 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to [Earl H.] Emmons, 1938 Apr 7; ALS, 2 p. w/env
  - James Branch Cabell to [Earl H.] Emmons, 1938 Apr 7; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Earl H.] Emmons, 1938 Apr 16; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Earl H.] Emmons, 1938 Apr 21; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Earl H.] Emmons, 1938 May 6; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Earl H.] Emmons, 1938 May 24; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Earl H.] Emmons, 1938 Jul 1; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Earl H.] Emmons, 1938 Jul 8; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Earl H.] Emmons, 1938 Jul 11; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Earl H.] Emmons, 1938 Aug 4; TLS, 1 p.
  - Christmas card, with printed signature, Mr & Mrs. James Branch Cabell, Bailard Hartwell Cabell, to Earl H. Emmons, Esq., 1940 Dec 20; Card w/env